[MUSIC]
[음악]
So for each model order that we might consider,
고려 대상인 각각의 모델 차수에 대해
for example, a linear model or
예를 들어 직선 모델이나
we also talked about using a quadratic model,
이차곡선 모델,
all the way up to our very crazy, 13th order polynomial.
13차 다항식까지 다뤘습니다
And of course, we could consider even higher order models.
물론 더 고차 모델도 고려할 수는 있습니다
Well, what happens to test error?
테스트 오류는 어떻게 되나요?
Sorry, I don't mean test error.
죄송합니다. 테스트 오류가 아니라
Let's start with training error.
훈련 오류부터 시작하죠
A lot easier to think about.
훨씬 이해하기가 쉽습니다
So training error.
훈련 오류
As we increase the model order, well, that models able
모델 차수를 증가시키면 시킬수록
to better and better fit the observations in that training dataset.
훈련 데이터 세트의 결과에 더 적합하게 맞춰집니다
So what we're gonna have is we're gonna have that our training error
즉 훈련 오류는 모델 차수를 증가시킬수록
decreases with increasing model order.
감소하죠
So remember the curves that we had.
전에 봤던 곡선을 되짚어 봅시다
We had the residual sum of squares associated with that linear fit,
회귀직선, 이차회귀곡선에서
quadratic fit, all the way up to the 13th order polynomial that basically hit
모든 결과에 부합하는 13차 다항식에
each one of those observations.
대응하는 잔차제곱합입니다
So, we saw that a residual sum of squares was going down and down and down.
잔차제곱합이 점점 감소함을 확인할 수 있습니다
So that's true even if we hold out some observations and
몇몇 결과를 따로 빼놓은 훈련 데이터 세트를 보면
just look at our training dataset.
이 가정이 참이라는 사실을 확인할 수 있습니다
So we're gonna have our training error decreasing and
모델의 유연성을 증가시킬수록
decreasing as we increase the flexibility of the model.
훈련 오류가 감소하는 것이죠
But, so let's just annotate this as being our training error,
여기에 예측 모델 파라미터 w 모자라고
particularly for our estimated model parameters w hat.
적어두죠
So let's be clear about what we mean by w hat.
w 모자가 무엇인지를 확실히 하고 넘어가죠
So for every model complexity such as linear model, quadratic model, and so on.
직선 모델, 이차곡선 모델 등의 모델 복잡도를 최적화하고
What we're gonna do is we're gonna optimize and
직선 모델 파라미터 w 모자를
find the parameters w hat for the linear model.
찾을 것입니다
We're searching over all possible lines minimizing the training error.
가능한 모든 선을 탐색해 훈련 오류를 최소화합니다
Remember that's what we said,
몇 슬라이드 전에 말씀드렸는데,
couple slides ago we said that the way we estimate our model is we're gonna
모델을 예측하는 방법은 훈련 데이터 세트 결과의 오류를
minimize the air on that observations in our training dataset.
최소화하는 것이라고 했습니다
So that's how we get w hat for the linear model,
직선 모델의 w 모자를 그렇게 구하고
and we compute the training error associated with that w hat.
그 w 모자에 대응하는 훈련 오류를 계산합니다
Then we look at all possible quadratic fits.
가능한 모든 이차회귀곡선을 살펴봅니다
Minimize the training error for over all the quadratic fits,
모든 이차회귀곡선에 대한 훈련 오류를 최소화해서
that's how we get w hat for the quadratic model.
이차곡선 모델의 w 모자를 구합니다
And then we plot the training error associated with the w hat for
그런 다음 이차곡선 모델의 w 모자에
the quadratic model and so on.
대응하는 훈련 오류 그래프를 그리는 것입니다
Well, we can also talk about test error, but
테스트 오류에 대해서도 논해볼 수 있지만
here it's a little bit more complicated because what do we think is gonna
이건 좀 복잡한데 모델 차수를 증가시킬수록
happen as we increase and increase our model order?
어떻게 될까요?
Well, what we saw, if you remember that 13th order polynomial fit,
꾸불꾸불한 13차 다항식 곡선을 기억하신다면
that really crazy wiggly line, we had really, really bad predictions.
아시겠지만 예측 정확도가 떨어집니다
So when we think about holding out our test data, fitting a 13th order
테스트 데이터를 따로 빼놓는다고 할 때
polynomial just on the training data, we're gonna get some wiggly, crazy fit.
훈련 데이터에만 13차 다항식을 적용하면 꾸불꾸불한 곡선이 나올 겁니다
And then when we look at those test observations, those houses that we
그런 다음 테스트 결과인 빼놓은 주택에
held out, we're probably gonna have very poor predictions of those actual values.
적용해 보면 예측이 실제 수치와 동떨어져 있을 확률이 높습니다
So what we're gonna expect is that at some point,
그러므로 예상가능한 건 어느 지점부터
our test error is likely to increase.
테스트 오류가 증가하리란 점입니다
So the curves for test error tend to look something like the following
테스트 오류 곡선은 주로 다음과 같은 모습이 되는데
where maybe the error is going down for some period of time but after a point
특정 지점까지는 오류가 감소하지만
The error starts to increase again.
그 후로는 다시 증가합니다
So here this curve is our test error for
모델이 훈련 데이터에 의해
these fitted models,
학습되었을 때
where the models were fit
모델에 대한 테스트 오류가
using the training data.
여기 이 곡선이 됩니다
So these are what curves tend to look like for training error and
훈련 오류와 테스트 오류를
test error as a function of model complexity, and
모델 복잡도에 대한 함수로 나타내면 이런 곡선이 됩니다
how we think about using these ideas to actually select the model or
이런 개념을 통해 예측을 위한
the complexity of the model that we should use for making our predictions.
모델, 모델 복잡도를 어떻게 선택할지에 대해선
We're gonna discuss in a lot more detail in the regression and
회귀와 분류 강의에서 훨씬 자세히
classification courses.
다룰 예정입니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]